<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/stylesheets/rss.css" type="text/css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gluttonous: Corporatizing Startups</title>
    <link>http://glu.ttono.us/articles/2006/05/23/corporatizing-startups</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description></description>
    <item>
      <title>Corporatizing Startups</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been in the &lt;a href="http://measuremap.com"&gt;Measure Map&lt;/a&gt; alpha since November and I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of the application, but one of the things that really helped me get enthusiastic about the operation was the small shop feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first really encountered the personality that I began to associate with the Measure Map team when I asked about blogging my experiences. I recieved a quick and personal reply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hi Kevin,&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re glad you&amp;#8217;re enjoying Measure Map so far.
    Absolutely, feel free to write about it, post
    screenshots, etc. &amp;#8211; but we do just ask you to 
    keep in mind that the product is in early alpha
    and that we&amp;#8217;ll be adding a ton of
    improvements/features soon.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Would you send us a link to your review?&lt;br/&gt;
    We&amp;#8217;d love to read it.  And thanks for helping
    us out by trying Measure Map during this alpha
    stage!&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Greg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast that with the reply I got yesterday about some problems with page loads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hello Kevin,&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email and the heads-up 
    concerning the pages failing to
    load. This is a known bug we are working on 
    getting resolved. We hope to
    roll-out fixes for a few known problems in the 
    near future.  Thank you
    again for helping us continue to test our alpha 
    product.  Please do
    continue to send feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Measure Map Support&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;hr/&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;To share your knowledge or learn from other
    Measure Map users, please
    visit the Measure Map Forum at:
    http://groups.google.com/group/measuremap-forums?lnk=li&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the change in tone? No name, only &amp;#8220;Measure Map Support&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that when projects are part of a big company, the company face is the one that is shown to the world, but when a small project is aquired should its personality be sacrificed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any, I&amp;#8217;d like to hear stories about companies or projects that survived being aquired or post mortems if you have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments are open.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;
It&amp;#8217;s important to note that I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; receive an instant message from Nick Seckar of the team about my email. This post, however, is really about the &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221; face of Measure Map and how it is shown through support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:b0090ea1-7245-46cd-86e8-860da3bdf565</guid>
      <author>kev</author>
      <link>http://glu.ttono.us/articles/2006/05/23/corporatizing-startups</link>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
